Gayathri Prakash Menon

gmenon2@illinois.edu |630-246-0313| gmenon.me

Objective

Gayathri is a diligent university student experienced in digital content creation, digital marketing and public relations. She has effectively been able to guide a team, brainstorm and implement content analytics, and successfully increase social media engagement. She is currently interested in furthering her career goals in marketing, public relations, or communications.

Education

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Urbana-Champaign

• Bachelor of Science in Media and Cinema Studies

Expected Graduation: May 2022

o GPA: 3.6

Technical Skills

• Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Audition, Microsoft Suite, Google Suite, Keela, and Mailchimp

Professional Experience

University Blood Initiative

Remote

Marketing and PR Liaison
Initiated multiple C-suite level meetings regarding fundraising strategies as the head of the PR team

- Grew social media followers by 25% in 4 months
- Rebranded official UBI website using SEO which increased website traffic by 20%

O Minor in Business, Public Relations, and Critical Film Production

• Conducted weekly converge scans, drafted press releases, and developed e-blasts to maintain proper social media interaction

University of Illinois- Illini Union

Champaign, IL

Sept 2020- Present

Multimedia Technician

Jan 2020- Present

- Implemented an efficient set up strategy by collecting all needed technology during the beginning of a shift
- Standardized all set up procedures to ensure all regular clients can manage technology on their own

Projects

Personal YouTube channel

Jan 2019- Present

- Launched channel to improve editing, camera work, and sound mixing
- Experimented with different methods of marketing and boosted personal brand

A Thanksgiving Selfie

Nov 2019

- Led sound recording team and used the Tascam DR-70D audio kit
- Standardized all settings in the audio kit days before the shoot to prevent any changes in sound levels
- Assisted the director in *Adobe Premiere Pro* and *Adobe Audition* to create flawless transition and edit any unwanted sound interferences

Snowflake on the Quad

Dec 2018

- Operated GoPro HERO 6 with GoPro Karma Grip and assisted the production set as Best Boy
- Utilized the GoPro Grip to shoot controlled panning shots to emphasis and bring attention to the size of the crowd
- Planned and created the GoPro shot list and effectively stuck to the list to ensure all shots were taken

Leadership Roles

College of Media Student Advisory Board Member

2019- Present

• Became one of first student ambassadors for the College of Media, represented current College of Media students, and worked with incoming freshman to answer any questions and show them everything the College of Media has to offer

Academic Misconduct and Capricious Grading Committee Board Member

2020- Present

• Worked with other board members to assess any academic misconduct and/or capricious grading situations and enforced academic and grading rules and regulations accordingly